Finding Aid for the Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Collection of Musical Works, ca.1920-ca.1980
UCLA Library, Performing Arts Special Collections
  - Sonnet Nr. XXXV (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Oct. 19th, 1963). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. CXXVIII. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Oct. 13, 1945). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. CXLVI ("Soul and Death"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 4, 1945). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Sonnet CVI (Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Aug. 20, 1945). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Sonnet Nr. CXVI (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 8th, 1945). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Alghe. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Alt Wein. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Chorale-Prelude. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Due Preludi per Organo. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - El Encanto. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Evangelicon. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Fugue. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Il Raggio Verde. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Introduction, Aria and Fugue. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Introitus. Manuscript. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Notturno. Manuscript. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Prayers My Grandfather Wrote. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Prelude. Published edition. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Prelude & Fugue. Manuscript. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Primavera Fiorentino. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Questo fu il Carro Morte. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Ricecare. Manuscript. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Six Canons for Piano. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Slow - with variations. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Sonatina Zoologica. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Stars. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. XC ("Hate"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 7, 1945). 4p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. XXX. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., July 3rd, 1944). 4p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. CII ("My love is strengthen'd"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Oct. 10, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. LXXIII ("Yellow Leaves"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 10, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. LIII ("The Mirror"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 22, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. CV ("Fair, kind and true"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 18, 1945). 6p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Sonnet Nr. LVII (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 15, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Sonnet Nr. LXIV (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Oct. 8, 1945). 4p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Sonnet Nr. LXV (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 13, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Sonnet Nr. XCIV (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Oct. 11, 1945). 12p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Sonnet Nr. XXVII (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Apr. 17, 1947). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Sonnet Nr. XXXII (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Oct. 12, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Stelle cadente. Rome: Forlivesi, 1919. 32p. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Three sonnets from the Portuguese. London: Chester, 1928. 15p. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    1. The sweet sad years; 2. Letters; 3. Poems and flowers For voice and piano.
  - Two Byron songs. Photocopy of autograph ms. (1941). 2p, 4p. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    1. Music on the waters (pp.1-2 only); 2. With silence and tears. For voice and piano.
  - V'erastich (Eternal love): from Songs and processionals for a Jewish wedding. New York: Mills, 1951. 5p. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Hebrew and English texts; Hosea, Chapter II, 21-22. For voice and piano.
  - Vocalise-étude: pour voix moyennes. Paris: Leduc, 1929. 7p. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Series title: Repertoire moderne de vocalises-études. For voice and piano.
  - Vos toig mir. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Feb. 9, 1964). 3p. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    For voice and piano. "A silly Jewish song, which I was commissioned to harmonize by the Cantors Assembly of America."--ink, p. 1.
  - 2 preghiere per i bimbi d'Ialia: poesie di Vamba (Luigi Bertelli). Florence: Forlivesi, 1925. 5p. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    1. Preghiera del mattino; 2. Preghiera della sera. For voice and piano.
  - Coplas: 11 liriche brevi. Florence: Forlivesi, 1919. 37p. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Die drei Konige (Die drei Magi). Florence: Forlivesi, 1933. 4p. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    "Poesia di H. Heine." For voice and piano.
  - Ninna nanna (per l'album di una bimba). Florence: Forlivesi, 1919. 4p. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    "Parole di U. C. T."
  - Five Shakespeare songs. London: Chester, 1924. 25p. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    1. Sigh no more, ladies; 2. How should I your true love know?; 3. Fear no more the heat O the sun; 4. Get you hence, for I must go; 5. Pardon, goddess of the Night.
  - Five Shakespeare songs: for contralto or baritone (Set 1). London: Chester, 1926. 26p. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    1. When daisies pied, and When icicles hang by the wall; 2. Tell me where is fancy bred; It was a lover and his lass; The poor soul sat sighing; 5. Hark! Hark! the lark.
  - Four Shakespeare songs: for baritone and piano. London: Chester, 1925. 14p. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    1. Immortal gods, I crave no pelf; 2. Come away, come away death; 3. Under the green-wood tree; 4. Blow, blow, thou winter wind.
  - Four Shakespeare songs: for tenor and piano (Set I). London: Chester, 1926. 18. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    1. Come unto these yellow sands, and Full fathom five; 2. Lawn as white as driven snow; 3. Take, O, take those lips away; 4. Who is Sylvia?
  - Four Shakespeare songs: for tenor and piano (Set II). London: Chester, 1925. 19p. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    1. When daffodils begin to peer; 2. What shall he have the kill'd the deer; 3. O mistress mine; 4. When that I was a little tiny boy.
  - Four Shakespeare songs: for soprano and piano. London: Chester, 1923. 20p. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    1. You spotted snakes with double tongue; 2. Fie on sinful fantasy; 3. Orpheus with his lute; 4. Where the bee sucks. "To Nick-my first Shakespearean adventure, with all best wishes for his 41st birthday-from Mario, Nov. 14, 1965"--ink, title page.
  - Shakespeare songs: Book X. London: Chester, 1926. 12p. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Six short songs from King Lear. For voice and piano.
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. XXXI ("All hearts"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif. Sept. 9, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Sonnet Nr. CIV. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif. July 18, 1944). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    ""This is one of my favorites."--pencil, p1. For voice and piano.
  - Sonnet Nr. LXXXVII. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif. Aug. 17, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Sonnet Nr. XCVII. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif. Aug. 29, 1945). 5p. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Sonnet Nr. XL. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif. Oct. 13-14, 1963). 4p. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Sonnet Nr. XLVII. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif. Oct. 21-22, 1963). 4p. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    "An extra bonus for Nov. 18, 1963"--ink, p1. For voice and piano.
  - 1st Trio (Full Score). (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 2nd String Quartet (Full Score). (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 2nd Trio (Full Score). (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Capitan Fracassa. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Ein Quartet-Satz. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Notturno Adriatico. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Ritmi. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Serentella. Published edition & Manuscript. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Signorine. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Sonata for Violin and Cello (Violin and Cello). (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Sonata for Violin and Viola (Violin and Viola). (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Sonata for Viola and Cello (Cello). (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - String Trio No. 1 (Full Score). (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - The Divan of Moses-ibn-Ezra. Published edition. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Fanfare. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Fantasia for Guitar. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Five Shakespeare Songs - Baritone. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Ecologues. Published edition. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Fiery Furnace. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - The Merchant of Venice. Libretto. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Naomi and Ruth. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Overture "La Bisbetica Domata". Published miniature score. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Birthday of the Infanta. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Capriccio Diabolico. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Concerto for 2 Guitars and Orchestra (piano score). (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - The Divan of Moses-ibn-Ezra (duplicate copy). (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - English Suite. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Valse Bluette (2). (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Vogelweide (duplicate Copy). (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Aira. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Canzonetta. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Nocturne. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Birthday of the Infanta. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Book of Ruth. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pastorale and Rondo, score (full) and parts: clarinet / violin / cello. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Ecologue. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Suite Nel Stile Italiano. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Vogelweide. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Bacco in Toscana. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - La Mandragola. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Savonarola. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 6 Pieces in the Form of Canon. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Aucassin et Nicolette. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The book of Jonah: a biblical oratorio, op. 151. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., May 10, 1951). 84p. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Concerto in Sol: per pianoforte e orchestra. Vienna, Leipzig: Universal, 1929. Piano reduction. 104p. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Divertimento for 2 Flutes, op. 119. New York: Weaner-Levant, 1945. 16p. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Photocopy of the published score.
  - The Importance of Being Earnest: three acts from Oscar Wilde's comedy. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 1st-Nov. 1st, 1961). 115p. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    A chamber opera for 8 singers, 2 pianos and percussion. Dedicated to Nino Rota. Pencil annotations.
  - The Merchant of Venice. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Nocturne in Hollywood. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - The Octoroon Ball. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Piano Sonata. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Poesia Svedese. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - 5 Humoresques on Themes of Stephen Foster. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - All's Well That Ends Well. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - An American Rhapsody. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Saul. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Rapsodia Napoletana. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Sacred Service for the Sabbath Eve. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - The Song of Songs. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Terrazze. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Tobias and the Angel, (formerly "The Book of Tobit", Part I, Part II, Part III). (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Tre Preludi Alpresti. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Violin Concerto No. 3. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Grand Street, Autumn 1989. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - A Tribute to Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, April 30, 1995. (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Photographs
  - (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Castelnuovo-Tedesco at a performance of the Florence Orchestra, Mascagni conducting (ca. 1903).
  - (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Castelnuovo-Tedesco in Usigliano, a favorite summer house and studio (1933 or 1934).
  - (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Castelnuovo-Tedesco in Briol with Gregor Piatigorsky, at the time they were reviewing the Cello Concerto (1934).
  - (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Castelnuovo-Tedesco in Florence (ca. 1935).
  - (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Castelnuovo-Tedesco in Hollywood, on the set at MGM for filming of "The Big Store" (1941).
  - (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Castelnuovo-Tedesco and Igor Stravinsky in Los Angeles (photo: James Arkatov).
  - (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Castelnuovo-Tedesco with Walter Gieseking (Los Angeles, 1955).
  - (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Castelnuovo-Tedesco at home in Beverly Hills.
  - The Clock. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    "Andantino"
  - Crime Doctor. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    "Intrigue"
    "Knockout Drops"
  - Dubarry Was A Lady. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    "The Duel"
  - Journey for Margaret. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    "Brave Margaret"
  - Keeping of the Flame. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    "Burning Papers"
    "Typewriting Montage"
  - Mask of the Avenger. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    1-B "Money Barrel"
    1-C "Count Killed"
    1-D "Captain Renaldo"
    1-E "Rinaldo Snubbed"
    6-D "Off They Trot"
    8-B "Avenger Unmasked"
  - Once Upon a Thursday. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    "Divorce"
  - Plan for Destruction. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    "Treachery"
  - Reunion. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    "Meeting Pat - Part 2"
  - Somewhere I'll Find You. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    "Chronicle"
    "Hanoi"
    "Paper Marriage"
  - Son of Lassie. (Box 24, Folder 11)
    "Skiing"
  - Tortilla Flat. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    "A New Deal"
    "The Pirate's Hut"
    "The Pirate's Money"
    "The Sweepers"
    "Vision in the Woods"
  - Vendetta Against a Dictator. (Box 24, Folder 13)
    "Burning Moscow"
  - White Cargo. (Box 24, Folder 14)
    "May Be One Day"
  - A Yank at Eton. (Box 24, Folder 15)
    "The Race"
  - In Modo Russo. (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Ballata dall' Esilio. (Box 24, Folder 17)
    includes letter
  - Naomi and Ruth. (Box 24, Folder 18)
    A small cantata for Women [sic] Voices from 'The Book of Ruth' (Chapter I)
  - Aria of Naomi. (Box 24, Folder 19)
    (from the cantata "Naomi and Ruth") (1949)
  - The Queen of Sheba. (Box 24, Folder 20)
    A small cantata for women's voices op: 161
  - Three Sephardi Songs. (Box 24, Folder 21)
    I. Montanas Altas; II. Ven y veras; III. Una noche alunar
  - Catalogue of Works - chronological. 111 pages. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Catalogue: 1910-1939 (pp. 1-87)
    Works without opus 1940-1968 (pp. 88-100)
    Transcriptions (pp. 101-111)
  - Catalogue of Works - by type of works. 87 pages. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Works for solo instruments and orchestra (8 pgs.)
    Works for narrator and orchestra (1 pg.)
    Works for narrator and instruments (1 pg.)
    Works written for orchestra (11 pgs.)
    Works adapted for orchestra (2 pgs.)
    Chamber music (10 pgs.)
    Music for solo guitar (14 pgs.)
    Works for guitar(s) and orchestra (3 pgs.)
    Chamber works with guitar (3 pgs.)
    Music for guitar and voice(s) or narrator (5 pgs.)
    Transcriptions for solo guitar (1 pg.)
    Transcription for guitar and harpsichord (1 pg.)
    Works for two guitars (2 pgs.)
    Overtures to Shakespeare's plays (4 pgs.)
    Piano music (20 pgs.)
    Music for violin (7 pgs.)
    Music with Jewish themes (12 pgs.)
    Piano concertos (2 pgs.)
  - Catalogue of guitar works. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    in alphabetical order
  - La Vita Nova. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Sonnet Nr. XL. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Come away, come away death. photocopy of published score. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "piccino, piccio..". published score. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Sonnet Nr. XCVIII. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Sonnet Nr. XL. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Sonnet Nr. XXVII. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Sonnet Nr. LVII. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Sonnet Nr. XCVIII. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Sonnet Nr. XXIX. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Sonnet Nr. LXIV. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Sonnet Nr. XXXI. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Sonnet Nr. LXXIII. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Sonnet Nr. LX. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Sonnet Nr. XXIX. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Sonnet Nr. XLVII. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - When that I was a little tiny boy. Ozalid copy. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Take O, take those lips away. Ozalid copy. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Sonnet Nr. VIII. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Sonnet Nr. XCVII. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Sonnet Nr. CIX. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Girotolido Dei Golosi. photocopy of autograph ms. (Box 26, Folder 22)